goalcast.com 2019-11-30

# Privacy Policy | Goalcast

**Privacy Policy – GOALCAST**

Goalcast Inc. (“ **Goalcast** ” or “ **we** ”) places particular importance on the protection of your Personal Information. That is why we are committed to ensure the accuracy, security and confidentiality of the Personal Information collected about you, in accordance with applicable laws. 

This Privacy Policy (the “ **Policy** ”) defines how Goalcast collects, uses, discloses and retains your Personal Information and is intended to help you understand our practices. By providing us with Personal Information, you consent to its processing in accordance with this Policy. 

This Policy does not apply to third-party websites and software (ex. Facebook, Youtube, Instagram, etc.) that may be accessed through our inspirational content website, transactional platform or application, as the case may be (collectively, our “ **Sites** ”). 

For the purposes of this Policy, “ **Personal Information** ” means any information about an identifiable individual, as defined in Canadian law.

Because Goalcast is all about trust, and to build that trust with its community, Goalcast has appointed a Chief Privacy Officer, which will answer any questions you have and address any comments or complaints about this Policy. Therefore, you may contact Anouare Abdou, Director of Operations at the following email address: Anouare (at) Goalcast (dot) com.

**1-THE PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

In the course of our business and provision of services, the Personal Information collected may include, but is not limited to:[

• Your first and last name;  
• Gender;  
• Your address;  
• Your email address;  
• Your IP address;   
• Your use of our Sites and other technical information relating to your browsing behaviour;   
• Data necessary to process your payment; and   
• Your order history.

We do not knowingly collect personal data about anyone under the age of 16.

**Except when it is truly essential, we will not refuse to provide services or sell you goods if you refuse to give us your Personal Information.** Goalcast may not refuse to respond to a request for goods or services or to a request relating to employment by reason of the applicant’s refusal to disclose Personal Information except where:

  * collection of that Personal Information is necessary for the conclusion or performance of a contract;
  * collection of that Personal Information is authorized by law; or
  * there are reasonable grounds to believe that the request is not lawful.

**2-HOW WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Goalcast collects your Personal Information from you and through cookies. 

**2.1 From you (you know, when you actually give us information about you)**

You provide us directly with Personal Information, such as when you create an account on our Sites, when you click on an advertisement that we have placed on a third party website (e. g. Google, Facebook, etc.), when you contact us, when you complete an online request form or when you purchase one of our products or services. 

**2.2 Cookies**

Cookies are collected on our Sites to give you a better experience while browsing our inspirational content or while buying our motivational products. They are not mandatory, so you can turn them off at anytime. 

Cookies are small data files that are commonly stored on your device when using websites and online services. They are used for the efficient operation of websites and can provide information and help personalize services. Goalcast collects Personal Information provided by cookies.

Goalcast uses different types of cookies:

  * Performance and functionality connection cookies: These cookies are not essential to the provision of our services. They facilitate the personalization and enhancement of the user experience. For example, they may remember your preferences and avoid having to re-enter information more than once or remember your credentials, so you don’t have to enter them each time you use them.

  * Cookies for advertising purposes: These cookies are not essential to the provision of our services. They use information about your visit to the site, such as the pages visited or the response to advertisements, to help provide the best user experience for your situation.

  * If you wish to disable the use of cookies, you can do so from your browser’s preference menu. You may disable cookies or use private browsing mode when using the Goalcast services.

**3-HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

**Why we collect your Personal Information.** Personal Information collected by Goalcast will be used for the following purposes:–

  * Provide, maintain, customize and improve our services;
  * Allow Goalcast to perform internal operations related to its services;
  * Allow Goalcast to better understand its business and its customers, generally with the purpose to improve our products and services and developing new ones;
  * Send or facilitate communications between Goalcast and you in connection with the services; and
  * Communicating with you and serving you tailored advertising both on and off our Sites.

**We will inform you if we intent to use your Personal Information for other purposes.** Except as already provided by applicable privacy legislation, Goalcast will request your consent before using your Personal Information for purposes not previously identified. 

**4-YOUR CONSENT TO THE COLLECTION AND USE**

**Prior to use your Personal Information we will require your consent.** Your consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information is required, except when inappropriate. (For example, for legal or security reasons, it may be impossible or impractical to obtain consent).

**If you browse our inspirational content or purchase our products, you are deemed to agree to this Policy.** By agreeing to use Goalcast’s services, you expressly provide Goalcast with your consent to collect, process and use your Personal Information in accordance with the provisions of this Policy.

**You understand this Policy.** You represent that you are aware of the purposes for which Goalcast collects, processes and uses your Personal Information, how it will be collected and how we protect the confidentiality of the Personal Information.

You may withdraw your consent at any time, subject to legal or contractual restrictions and reasonable notice. 

**5-RETENTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

**We will retain your Personal Information for an undefined period of time.** Personal Information will be retained as long as necessary for the fulfillment of the identified purposes or for compliance with legal requirements regarding retention periods.

**You may delete your account.** Any user may request that their account be deleted by sending a request to Goalcast by email.

**6-OUR SECURITY MEASURES**

**We try our best to keep your Personal Information safe.** Goalcast implements industry-standard security measures to protect its customers from unauthorized access or use, alteration, unlawful or accidental destruction or loss of their Personal Information.

**Sadly, not everybody is well-intentioned, and we cannot guaranty we will not get hacked.** Unfortunately, it is impossible for us to guarantee the absolute security of the Personal Information collected or transmitted through our Sites. You therefore understand and agree that (i) there are limits to the security and confidentiality of the Personal Information we collect that are beyond the control of Goalcast; (ii) the security, integrity and confidentiality of all Personal Information and data exchanged between you and Goalcast through our Sites cannot be guaranteed; and (iii) such Personal Information may be viewed or altered by a third party at the time of the transfer. For these reasons, Goalcast cannot be held responsible for any loss, capture or alteration of Personal Information. 

**7-ACCESS AND MODIFICATION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

**You can change your account information yourself.** You have access to your Personal Information through your user account on our Sites, if applicable. You can correct and update this Personal Information from this access.

**You may obtain copy of your Personal Information and have it corrected.** You may obtain a copy of your Personal Information or have it corrected, if it is incorrect, by sending us a written request by e-mail. 

**Before we consider any request, we must make sure that you are who you say you are.** No request for access, rectification or deletion may be considered unless it is made in writing by you when you prove that you are the individual concerned (or the representative, heir or successor of that individual, or the liquidator of the succession, a beneficiary of life insurance or of a death benefit). 

**We will address your request fast.** When we receive a request for access, rectification or removal, we will attempt to respond within a reasonable timeframe after receipt of the request.

**In some cases, we might not be able to provide you everything you ask for.** In certain situations, Goalcast may not be able to provide access to all the Personal Information it holds about you. Exceptions to the access requirement are meant to be limited and specific. The reasons for denying access will be provided to you upon request. 

**Some examples why we could refuse your request.** Exceptions may include information that is prohibitively costly to provide, information that contains references to other individuals, information that cannot be disclosed for legal, security or proprietary commercial reasons and information that is subject to solicitor-client or litigation privilege.

A reasonable fee may be charged for the transcription, reproduction or transmission of Personal Information.

**8-PERSONAL INFORMATION DISCLOSURE**

Goalcast will not disclose your Personal Information to a third party unless you consent, or unless such disclosure or use is required by law.

**We may share your Personal Information to third parties, so that you may get information about stuff that you care about.** We may share your Personal Information with advertising partners in order to provide you targeted advertisement, either on our Sites or on those third-parties websites. Those partners may also use cookies, notably to track the effectiveness of those ads. 

**We may share aggregated data for research purposes.** Personal Information may also be disclosed without your consent for research purposes if the documents containing the Personal Information are not structured so as to allow retrieval by reference to your name or identifying code or symbol and the Personal Information cannot be retrieved by means of such a reference.

**9-POLICY CHANGE AND UPDATE**

**We may modify our Policy from time to time.** Goalcast may, at its discretion, update, revise, modify or supplement this Policy from time to time. If a change is made to the Policy, you will be notified when you log in and/or we will send you a link to the new version of the Policy. The Policy and any related agreements, if any, will be posted on our Sites. Goalcast asks its users to consult the amended Policy before continuing to use its services. If you refuse the updated version of the Policy, you will be able to terminate your account.

**If you continue to use our Sites, you have agreed to the new Policy.** The continued use of the services provided by Goalcast, after the amended Policy comes into effect, constitutes consent to such amended Policy.

**10-POSSIBILITY TO FILE A COMPLAINT**

**We try to be the best at what we do, but you can make a complaint if something is wrong.** Goalcast has established procedures to receive complaints and inquiries about its policies and practices for the management of Personal Information. The complaints procedure is easily accessible and simple to use.

**We will accompany you in the process of a complaint and we promise to address it with care.** Goalcast will inform persons making an inquiry or complaint of the existence of the relevant procedures. Goalcast will investigate all complaints. If a complaint is found to be justified, Goalcast will take appropriate measures, including, if necessary, amending its policies and practices.

* * *
